# RITESH GUPTA

# (Senior Frontend Engineer)

**(**\_+91-7045002101

rgriteshguptha@gmail.com

rg4897.github.io

in linkedin.in/rgriteshguptha

Thane, MH, India github.com/rg4897

#### CAREER SUMMARY:

Innovative Senior Frontend Engineer with over 5+ years of experience in developing high-impact web applications. I aim to contribute with my skills to an organization where I can support its goals while advancing my professional career and making a positive impact on society through my work.

## **SKILLS:**

#### Languages

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3

#### Frameworks

Node JS, Angular, React, Redux, MVC, Bootstrap, iQuery, Tailwind CSS, SCSS/SASS, Astro

#### OS & Database Experiences

Linux, Windows, MySQL, PostgreSQL

#### Tools

Docker, AWS, GitHub & Gitlab CI/CD, Github Pages, Jira, Postman, VSCode, Selenium, ChatGPT

# **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

IPLit Solutions LLP, Senior Frontend Engineer

(Apr 2021 - Present)

- Performance Optimization: Developed and implemented custom React hooks for debouncing and throttling API requests, utilized request batching, and cached responses when appropriate, which resulted in a 20% performance improvement in the Bahmni application, leading to savings of approximately \$10M USD.
- Onsite Experience: Conducted multiple site visits to thoroughly understand workflows and user requirements, which enabled the development of tailored healthcare software solutions for the Bihar and Assam governments, resulting in an 80% increase in their digital accessibility.
- Project Delivery: Spearheaded and successfully delivered 18+ implementations, demonstrating exceptional project management skills.
- Leadership & Mentorship: Interviewed 5+ candidates and mentored junior developers, fostering team growth, skill development, and promoting Agile methodologies for efficient collaboration and project delivery.

# **IPLit Solutions LLP**, Software Engineer

(Jul 2019 - Apr 2021)

- Improved Code Reusability: Wrote and troubleshooted JavaScript, HTML, and CSS codes on various platforms for Bahmni and it's native applications, resulting in improved usability and user experience across the board.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines: Designed and optimized CI/CD pipelines to automate testing, integration, and deployment processes, significantly reducing release times and improving code quality.
- Cloud Infrastructure Management: I deployed and managed frontend applications on AWS EC2 instances, leveraging Elastic Load Balancing, which resulted in a 35% reduction in application loading time, saving approximately 1500ms.

#### **PROJECTS:**

Bahmni, Senior Frontend Engineer 🗹

(Jul 2019 - Present)

- Contributed to Open Source HMIS Software: Played a key role in enhancing an open- source HMIS web application like Bahmni and played a pivotal role in developing critical frontend modules.
- **Developed Key Modules:** Led the development of significant features and functionalities, driving improvements in the software's usability and performance.
- **Technologies Used:** 
  - AWS services
  - JavaScript
  - React
  - Redux
- Angular
- TypeScript
- HTML5 & CSS3
- MySQL, PostgreSQL
- GitHub & Gitlab CI/CD Node JS
- Docker
- JSON
- MVC
- Postman
- ChatGPT SCSS/SASS
- BootStrap
- Selenium

# My Portfolio Website, Freelance Web Developer

(Apr 2023 - May 2024)

- Developed a Personal Portfolio Site: Crafted a dynamic and responsive personal portfolio using advanced web development techniques and frameworks. Integrated a contact management system and optimized the site for performance and scalability. Deployed the site on a version-controlled hosting platform for seamless updates and maintenance.
  - HTML5 & CSS3
- Typescript
- JavaScript
- Google Forms

React

- GitHub Pages
- Bootstrap
- Astro

### **EDUCATION:**

# Terna Engineering College | Mumbai University

(2014-2018)

Bachelor of Computer Science - Software Engineering

• Completed the degree with 6.5/10 CGPA

# **CERTIFICATION:**

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures 🖸

(Aug 2023 - Jun 2024)

FreeCodeCamp (1)